Mexican Government Documents Regarding the Borderlands Campaign Against the Apache Indians, 1832-1946
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Mexican Government Documents Regarding the Borderlands Campaign Against the Apache Indians, 1832-1946
MS 367
University of Arizona Library.Special Collections
This collection documents relations between the Mexico and the United States during the mid to late 1800's. Of particular importance is the impact of Apache movements through Sonora and Arizona. Documents include administrative, diplomatic and military correspondence, administrative journals, military testimonies, and financial and statistical records.
5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
This collection consists of the original collection and a preservation copy collection. There are no restrictions to access for the preservation copies of this collection however scholars must receive special permission to access the original collection.
Organization
This collection is organized into 2 series.
Preservation Copy, 1832-1946
Original Copy, 1832-1946
Scope and Content Note
This collection is arranged by date. The order of the preservation copies corresponds exactly to the original copies..
Access Terms
Mexican-American Border Region -- History -- 19th century.
Mexican-American Border Region -- Archives -- 19th century.
Apache Indians -- Arizona -- History -- 19th century.
Apache Indians -- Sonora (Mexico: State) -- History -- 19th century.
Sonora (Mexico: State) -- History -- 19th century -- Sources.
Container List
- Series 1: Preservation Copy, 1832-1946
  - 1832 April-October (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1848 March-December (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1849 February-1850 June (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1852 January-1853 December (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1862 April-1876 September (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1877 March-May (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1877 May (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1877 June 1-14 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1877 June 15-July 6 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1877 July 7-October 2 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1877 October 3-18 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1877 October 19-November 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1877 November 12-December 31 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1878-1879 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1882 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1883 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1884 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1885 May-June (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1885 July 1-18 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1885 July 22-30 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1885 August 2-6 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1885 August 7-16 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1885 August 17-31 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1885 September 1-8 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1885 September 10-18 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1885 September 19-27 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1885 October 1-7 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1885 October 8-31 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1885 November (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1885 December (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1885-1886 (Box 2, Folder 13-16)
  - 1886 January (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1886 February (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1886 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1886 March (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
  - 1886 March 31-November 12 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1887-1946 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Series 2: Original Copy, 1832-1946
  - 1832 April-October (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1848 March-December (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1849 February-1850 June (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1852 January-1853 December (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1862 April-1876 September (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1877 March-May (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1877 May (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1877 June 1-14 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1877 June 15-July 6 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1877 July 7-October 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1877 October 3-18 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1877 October 19-November 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1877 November 12-December 31 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1878-1879 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1880-1881 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1882 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1883 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1884 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1885 May-June (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1885 July 1-18 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1885 July 22-30 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1885 August 2-6 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1885 August 7-16 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1885 August 17-31 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1885 September 1-8 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1885 September 10-18 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1885 September 19-27 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1885 October 1-7 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1885 October 8-31 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1885 November (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1885 December (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1885-1886 (Box 4, Folder 13-16)
  - 1886 January (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 1886 February (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 1886 March 15 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 1886 March (Box 4, Folder 20-22)
  - 1886 March 31-November 12 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 1887-1946 (Box 4, Folder 24)